Finding aid for Department of Afroamerican and African Studies (University of Michigan) records, 1966-2010 (bulk 1970-1994)
Bentley Historical Library
- Organizational archives of CAAS, 1962-2010
  - Library, 1970-2000
    - America's Greatest Negroes, 1970 (Box 16)
    - Bibliographies, 1970-1992; 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Class Handouts, 1986 (Box 16)
    - Exhibits, 1980-1992
      - Black History Month, Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 16)
      - Black History Month, Publicity, 1980-1981 (Box 16)
      - Black History Month, Wesley, Charles, 1980-1981 (Box 16)
      - Black Odyssey, 1981-1982 (Box 16)
      - Jules Bledsoe, 1981-1982 (Box 16)
      - Calendar, 1991-1992; 12 folders (Box 16)
      - Immigration and Blacks (Box 16)
      - Malcolm X, Undated (Box 16)
      - King, Martin Luther, Undated (Box 16)
    - Librarians, Glover, Denise, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 16)
    - Librarians, Hall, Jo Anne, Correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 16)
    - Librarians, Hortense, Howard, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 16)
    - Librarian procedures (Box 16)
    - Manual, 1987 (Box 16)
    - Mazrui Collection Bibliographic Project, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Programs and Events (Box 16)
    - Programs and Events, Porter, Dorothy, 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    - Projects, Acquisitions Catalog, 1989-1992 (Box 16)
    - Proposals, Undated (Box 16)
    - Public Relations, 1986-1990 (Box 16)
    - Public Relations, Open House, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Reports, 1978-2000 (Box 16)
    - Statistics, 1988; 1997 (Box 16)
  - Persons, faculty, 1962-2005
    - Adebiyi, Nike, 1989 (Box 17)
    - Allen, Bazel, 1980-1985 (Box 17)
    - Allen, Richard, 1986-1987 (Box 17)
    - Allen, Walter R., 1976-1989 (Box 17)
    - Allen, Walter R., Publications, 1978-1989; 5 folders (Box 17)
    - Askew, Kelly, 1999-2005 (Box 17)
    - Atkins, Keletso, 1983-1995 (Box 17)
    - Atkins, Keletso, Publications, 1986-1995; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Awkward, Michael, 1985-1995 (Box 17)
    - Awkward, Michael, Publications, 1993-1997 (Box 17)
    - Baddo, Jean Paul (Box 17)
    - Boubacar, Barry, 1995 (Box 17)
    - Bowman, Phillip, 1980-1991 (Box 17)
    - Bonilla-Silva, Eduardo, undated (Box 17)
    - Brown, Elsa Barkley, 1990-1996 (Box 17)
    - Bryant, Bunyan, 1981-1990 (Box 17)
    - Chrisman, Robert, 1989-1993 (Box 17)
    - Clark, Gracia, 1988-1992 (Box 17)
    - Clark, Gracia, Publications, 1988-1992 (Box 17)
    - Cogburn, Derrick, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Cooper, Frederick, 1983-1993 (Box 17)
    - Cruse, Harold, 1970-2005 (Box 17)
    - Cruse, Harold, Bibliography, 1992-1993 (Box 17)
    - Cruse, Harold, Biography and Interviews, 1973-1988 (Box 17)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications, 1950-1978 (Box 17)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications, Book and Play Reviews, 1969-1971 (Box 18)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications, Book Reviews of "Crisis", 1967-1991; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications, Book Reviews of "Plural But Equal", 1981-1991 (Box 18)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications, Book Reviews of "Rebellion or Revolution", 1968-1973 (Box 18)
    - Cruse, Harold, Publications, Essays, 1962-1979; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Davis-Roberts, Christopher, 1977-1985 (Box 18)
    - Dawson, Michael, 1988-1993 (Box 18)
    - Dawson, Michael, Publications, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Demerson, Bamidele, 1974-1987 (Box 18)
    - Deskins, Donald, 1990-1992 (Box 18)
    - Deskins, Donald, Publications, 1969-1984 (Box 18)
    - Diouf, Mamadou, 2003 (Box 18)
    - Dykes, Jr., DeWitt, 1988-1992 (Box 18)
    - Enyia, Dike Ogbuefi, 1975-1979 (Box 18)
    - Enyia, Dike Ogbuefi, Syllabi, 1975-1980; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Edie, Carlene J., Publications, 1988; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Esonwanne, Uzoma, 1990-1992 (Box 18)
    - Evans, Billy J., 1990 (Box 18)
    - Eyetsemition, Frank, 1980-1990 (Box 18)
    - Farley, Reynolds, 1986 (Box 18)
    - Fields, Barbara J., 1920-1990 (Box 18)
    - Flanagan, Brenda, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Francis, Jacqueline, 2003 (Box 18)
    - Gaines, Kevin, 1990-2006 (Box 18)
    - Gish, Oscar, 1979-1981 (Box 18)
    - Goduka, Ivy, 1987 (Box 18)
    - Grovoqui, Siba, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Hadjor, Kofi B., 1985-1987 (Box 18)
    - Hall, Jo Anne, 1985-1994 (Box 18)
    - Hamer, Alice, 1986 (Box 18)
    - Haniff, Nesha, 1987-1990 (Box 18)
    - Hayden, Robert, Essays, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Holl, Augustin, 2007 (Box 18)
    - Holt, Thomas C., 1982-1991 (Box 18)
    - Holt, Thomas C., Publications, 1982-1992; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Jackson, Charles A., 1990 (Box 19)
    - Jackson, James, 1989-2003 (Box 19)
    - Jackson, Murray, 1991 (Box 19)
    - Jessye, Eva A., 1976-1992 (Box 19)
    - Johnson, Lemuel, 1986-2002 (Box 19)
    - Johnson, Lemuel, Publications, 1969-2000; 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Jones, Gayl, 1975-1984 (Box 19)
    - Kelley, Robin, 1991-1994 (Box 19)
    - Kelley, Robin, Publications, 1984-1994; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Kolole, Omari, Publications, 1984-1987 (Box 19)
    - Lawal, Babatunde, 1990-1991 (Box 19)
    - Lawrence, Morris, 1962-1980; 4 folders (Box 19)
      (photo in folder two)
    - Lewis, Earl, 1989-1994 (Box 19)
    - Lewis, Earl, South Africa Project, 1991-1992; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Lewis, Earl, Publications, 1987-1996 (Box 19)
    - Lewis, Earl, "At Work and At Home" book MS, 1988; 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Omer, Afaf, 1992 (Box 19)
    - Lindsay, Lisa, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Lockard, Jon, 1985-2007 (Box 20)
    - Lockard, Jon, Publications, 1983-1997 (Box 20)
    - Locke, Rovan, 1977 (Box 20)
    - McLoyd, Vonnie, 1987 (Box 20)
    - McLoyd, Vonnie, Publications, 1979-1983; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Makoni, Sinfree, 2000 (Box 20)
    - Mitchell, Michele, 2004 (Box 20)
    - Moody, Charles, 1992 (Box 20)
    - Morris, Aldon, 1981-1986 (Box 20)
    - Norman, Martha, 1989 (Box 20)
    - Owusu, Maxwell, 1978-1996 (Box 20)
    - Patton, Sharon, 1983-1993 (Box 20)
    - Patton, Sharon, Publications, 1983-1992 (Box 20)
    - Porter, Cornelia, 1991 (Box 20)
    - Quarcoopome, Nii, 1990-1993 (Box 20)
    - Ransby, Barbara, 1988-1989 (Box 20)
    - Ransby, Barbara, Publications, 1987-1990 (Box 20)
    - Richard, Glen, 1991 (Box 20)
    - Roberts, Allen, 1982-1988 (Box 20)
    - Roberts, Allen, Publications, 1979-1986; 5 folders (Box 20)
    - Roberts, Allen, Refrigerator Project, Mr. Wizard, 1983-1984 (Box 20)
      (includes photo)
    - Ross, Richard, Publications, undated. (Box 20)
    - Samoff, Joel, Publications, 1979 (Box 20)
    - Scott, Rebecca, 1986-1991 (Box 20)
    - Shepherd, Verne, Publications, 1991 (Box 20)
    - Shirley, George, 1988-1989 (Box 20)
    - Standifer, James, 1985-2000 (Box 20)
    - Stone, Pauline, 1979-1982 (Box 20)
    - Stone, Pauline, Publications, 1975-1980; 1 folder (Box 20)
      (1 of 5 folders)
    - Stone, Pauline, Publications, 1975-1980; 4 folders (Box 21)
      (2-5 of 5 folders)
    - Sudarkasa, Niara, 1981-1992 (Box 21)
    - Sudarkasa, Niara, Publications, 1963-1987; 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Theoharis, Jeanne, undated (Box 21)
    - Tillery, Alvin, 2004 (Box 21)
    - Twumasi, Yaw, undated (Box 21)
    - Ukadike, Nwachukwu Frank, 1990-1992 (Box 21)
    - Ukadike, Nwachukwu Frank, Publications, 1988-1994 (Box 21)
    - Uzoigwe, Godfrey, 1981 (Box 21)
    - Uzoigwe, Godfrey, Publications, 1971-1988; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Wagaw, Teshome, 1981-1999 (Box 21)
    - Wagaw, Teshome, Publications, 1971-1991; 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Walton, Hanes, 1990 (Box 21)
    - Whatley, Warren, 1983-1996 (Box 21)
    - Wilson, Ernest, 1984-1989 (Box 21)
    - Wilson, Francille, undated (Box 21)
    - Woods, Ronald, 1980-1982 (Box 21)
    - Young, Alford, 1998 (Box 21)
    - Zafar, Rafia (Box 21)
    - Associates, 1971-1993 (Box 21)
    - Directories, 1977-2004 (Box 21)
    - Exchange Programs, Benin, 1981-1987 (Box 21)
    - Exchange Programs, South Africa, 1991 (Box 21)
    - Leave and Space, 1983-1985 (Box 22)
    - Research and Teaching Assistants, 1991-1994 (Box 22)
    - Research Seminars, 1993-1994 (Box 22)
    - Searches, 1987-1993 (Box 22)
  - Persons, non-faculty, 1986-2001
    - Staff, 1988-1989 (Box 22)
    - Visiting Scholars
      - Non-Parks-King Chavez, 1986-1990 (Box 22)
      - Parks-King-Chavez Program, 1990-1994; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Moody Scholars, Zhuwau, Thomas, 2001 (Box 22)
  - Programs and events, 1972-2002
    - Chronological files, 1972-2004; 10 folders (Box 22)
    - Black History Month, 1978-2002 (Box 22)
    - Black History Month, Rosa Parks and Kwame Toure, 1983 (Box 22)
    - Christmas Celebrations, 1987-1993 (Box 22)
    - College Day, 1987-1988 (Box 22)
    - Film Series, 1992-1993 (Box 22)
    - Graduate Receptions, 2001-2002 (Box 22)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr., Commemorations, 1990-1995; 2002; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Open House, 1983; 1990-1994 (Box 22)
    - Post-Doctoral, DuBois-Mandela-Rodney Fellowship, 1988-1995 (Box 22)
    - Workshops, 1991-2000
      - Inventions of Africa, 1991-1992 (Box 22)
      - New Nations and New Relations in the Post-Cold War World, 1994 (Box 22)
      - African Workshop, 1998 (Box 22)
      - Material Processes: Textiles and Texts in the African Diaspora, 2000 (Box 22)
  - Publications, 1971-2000
    - Brochures, 1975-2000 (Box 22)
    - CAAS News, 1993 (Box 22)
    - Black Faculty and Staff Directories, 1974-1983; 1993 (Box 22)
    - Discussion Papers, Black Educational Achievement Over the Life-Course, 1988; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Guide to Procedures and Services, 1989-1993 (Box 22)
    - Monograph and Report Series, 1971 (Box 22)
    - News and Notes, 1988; 2001-2003 (Box 22)
    - Newsletters, Series 01 and 02, 1970; 1973 (Box 22)
    - Newsletters, Series 03 ("Ozi Oma"), 1973 (Box 22)
    - Newsletters, Series 04, 1974-1975 (Box 22)
    - Newsletters, Series 05, 1984-1990; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Newsletters, The Tide, volume one, 1971 (Box 22)
      (1 of 2 folders)
    - Newsletters, The Tide, volume one, 1971 (Box 23)
      (2 of 2 folders)
    - Reviews of CAAS Publications, 1986 (Box 23)
    - South Africa Initiatives Office (SAIO) Update, 2000 (Box 23)
    - Voices of the African Diaspora, 1990-1994; 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Research projects, 1982-1997
    - Chikwaka Rural Hospital, Zimbabwe, 1983 (Box 23)
    - Contemporary History Project, Undated (Box 23)
    - Detroit Politics Bibliographic Project, 1988-1990 (Box 23)
    - Ford Foundation Project, 1990-1997; 8 folders (Box 23)
    - Ford Foundation Project: Michael Naylor Proposal re: Oakland University, 1991 (Box 23)
    - Gender and Campus Race Differences in Black Student Performance, 1986; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Immigration and Black Ethnicity in the United States, 1983 (Box 23)
    - National Study of Black College Students, 1982-1986 (Box 23)
    - Parks-King-Chavez Fellowship Mini-Course, Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 23)
    - Parks-King-Chavez Fellowship Mini-Course, Guest Speakers, 1987-1988 (Box 23)
    - Post-Emancipation Societies Project, 1985-1992 (Box 23)
    - Program for Research on Black Americans, 1984 (Box 23)
    - Robert Hayden Film Archive, 1990 (Box 23)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1992-1997 (Box 23)
    - Separate and Unequal The Racial Divide (Detroit), 1989 (Box 24)
    - Update on Student Retention, 1989 (Box 24)
  - Rodney, Walter, Student Essay Competition, 1985-1997
    - General, 1985-1997 (Box 24)
      [Access to this folder is restricted to the Bentley Historical Library reading room]
  - Study abroad, 1986-2005
    - Caribbean, 1989; 3 folders (Box 24)
      (Transcripts of lectures by Kathleen Drayton, Ricky Singh, Aggrey Brown, George Lamming, Stanley Greaves)
    - Jamaica, 1991-1995; 2 folders (Box 24)
      [Access to digitized content is enabled for the University of Michigan campus IP range and remote users who are able to authenticate via the University of Michigan weblogin. Access to folder 2 is restricted to the Bentley Historical Library reading room.]
    - South Africa, 2002; 2005 (Box 24)
    - West Africa, Benin, 1986-1988 (Box 24)
    - West Africa, Ghana, 2002; 2005 (Box 24)
    - West Africa, Ghana, Student Letters from, 1970; 1999 (Box 24)
  - Working papers, 1990-1998
    (Some papers are related to the First Annual Graduate Student Multidisciplinary Conference (1991), others to "Remapping of Scholarship: African Peoples in the Industrial Age," CAAS colloquia, and student essay prizes.)
    - 22. Siba N. Grovogui, 1990 (Box 24)
    - 23. Guyora Binder, 1990 (Box 24)
    - 24. Mary Alice Parker, 1991 (Box 24)
    - 25. Thomas Holt, 1991 (Box 24)
    - 26. Nancy Davis Corley, 1991 (Box 24)
    - 27. Angela Winand, 1991 (Box 24)
    - 28. Otto Gonzalez,1991 (Box 24)
    - 29. Nancy Racquel Mirabel, 1991 (Box 24)
    - 30. Tracye Matthews, 1991 (Box 25)
    - 31. Kyra Gaunt, 1991 (Box 25)
    - 32. Timothy D. Taylor, 1991 (Box 25)
    - 33. Bilinda Straight, 1991 (Box 25)
    - 34. Todd C. Shaw, 1991 (Box 25)
    - 42. Robin D. G. Kelley, 1992 (Box 25)
    - 44. Uzo Esonwanne, 1992 (Box 25)
    - 47. Babacar, Fall 1993 (Box 25)
    - 50. Sylvia Wynter, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 52. Nahum D. Chandler, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 53. Antonio Sergio Alfredo Guimaraes, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 54. Denise A. Herd, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 55. Carolyn Cooper, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 56. Abiola Irele, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 57. Martha Abreu, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 58. Antonio Sergio Alfredo Guimaraes, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 59. Draft Conference Papers, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 60. Tyler Stovall, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 61. Joe W. Trotter, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 62. Warren Whatley and Gavin Wright, 1994 (Box 25)
    - 63. Colloquium Series, 1994-1995 (Box 25)
    - 64. Robert W. Slenes, 1995 (Box 25)
    - 68. David M. Freund, 1995 (Box 25)
    - 77. Earl Lewis and Heidi Ardizzone, 1996 (Box 25)
    - 78. Elizabeth Higginbotham, 1996 (Box 25)
    - 84. Kwesi Yankah, 1996 (Box 25)
    - 88. Matthew Countryman, 1997 (Box 25)
    - 89. David Nicholls, 1996 (Box 25)
    - 90. Kathleen Malone O'Connor, 1997 (Box 25)
    - 93. Jean-Paul Bado, 1997 (Box 25)
    - 95. Patsy Lewis, 1997 (Box 25)
    - 96. Erin N. Winkler, 1997 (Box 25)
    - 97. Patrick B. Hill, 1997 (Box 25)
    - 98. Adrian Burgos, Jr., 1997 (Box 25)
    - 99. Mimi Sheller, 1997 (Box 25)
    - 101. Bob W. White, 1997 (Box 25)
    - 103. Teshome G. Wagaw, 1997 (Box 25)
    - 108. Danielle R. Washington, 1998 (Box 25)
    - 109. Gail J. Drakes, 1998 (Box 25)
    - African Peoples in the Industrial Age, David G. Nicholls, Jeanne F. Theoharis, Amy Jordan-Rahman, 1996 (Box 25)
    - African Peoples in the Industrial Age, Kate Masur, Hajj Malik Womack, 1996 (Box 25)
    - Colloquium Series, Heather Ann Thompson, Brian Meeks, Maria Helena P.T. Machado, 1996-1997 (Box 25)
    - Colloquium Series, P. Jane Splawn, Rafia Zafar, Dieudonné-Christophe Mbala Nkanga, 1997-1998 (Box 25)
    - Constructions of Manhood and Womanhood, Michael Awkward, Waldo E. Johnson Jr., 1996 (Box 25)
    - Constructions of Manhood and Womanhood, Elsa Barkley Brown, Marlon B. Ross, 1996 (Box 25)
    - Exploring the Dimensions of Life, Timothy Burke, Samuel Martinez, Nwachukwu Frank Ukadike, 1993-1994 (Box 25)
    - Exploring the Dimensions of Life, Sidney Chalhoub, Nantang Jua, 1995 (Box 25)
    - Exploring the Dimensions of Life, Matthew J. Countryman, Heinz Klug, Donna D. Daniels, 1995-1996 (Box 25)
    - Historical Perspectives, Jonathan Simon, Thomas C. Holt, Sidney Chalhoub, Verene A. Shepherd, 1991-1992 (Box 25)
    - New Nations and New Relations, Benigna Zimba, 1995 (Box 25)
    - Postemancipation Societies, Glen Richards, Frederick Cooper, Ada Ferrer, 1991 (Box 25)
    - Postemancipation Societies, Earl Lewis, 1991 (Box 25)
    - Transformations of Power and Culture in Africa, Veit Erlmann, Kelly M. Askew, Winifred C. Nweke, Tiyanjana Maluwa, 1996 (Box 25)
  - Photographs, 1977-1994; undated
    - Art (Box 27)
    - Baker Mandela Center Artwork and Photos, undated; 3 folders (Box 27)
    - CAAS 20th Anniversary, 1991 (Box 27)
    - CAAS visitors (identified), undated (Box 27)
    - Comprehensive Studies Program Mentoring Program, undated (Box 27)
    - Dated negatives, 1987; 1993 (Box 27)
    - Dated photo shoot, 1985 (Box 27)
    - Dated photos, 1990; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Identified people (Box 27)
    - Kwame Ture and Rosa Parks, 1983 (Box 27)
    - Lockard murals (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified, undated; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Negatives for Lockard and BAM Conference poster (Box 27)
    - Sharyl L. White Photos, 1977 (Box 27)
    - South African Initiatives Office, 1993 (Box 27)
    - Study Abroad Jamaica photos and slides, 1991-1995; 4 folders (Box 27)
    - Teshome Wagaw Ethiopian Study, undated (Box 27)
    - Women of Color Task Force Career Conferences, undated (Box 27)
    - Zeta Phi Beta Sorority, undated (Box 27)
  - Posters
    - 8 posters and one certificate (Folder FimuC26)
- Audio recordings on cassettes, 1975-2001
  The series "Audio recordings on cassettes" contains 486 cassettes, and largely consists of spoken word recordings of talks and professional meetings. Many of these cassettes have been digitized. The quality of these recordings is uneven -- some are very good, and others were made with portable recording equipment by volunteers. Because of uncertainty about the copyright status of these recordings, the digitized files are available for use in the reading room only.
  The cassettes are divided into seventeen subseries, arranged chronologically unless otherwise indicated: Early recorded speakers, tapes 1-76, 1975-1984 (arranged alphabetically by speaker's name); Jamaica Study Abroad Program, tapes 77-109, 1991 (arranged by tape number designated by CAAS); Gender and Urban Poverty Conference, tapes 110-116, 1996; Brown bag talks, tapes 117-202, 1986-1995; Dialogue series, tapes 203-221, 1991-1993; Robert Hayden Memorial, tapes 222-235, 1990, Workshop on Strengthening CAAS and Africana Studies at U-M, tapes 236-243, 1989, CAAS Symposium for Black History Month: Black American Families, tapes 244-253, 1991, Inventions of Africa: Africa in the Literatures of the Continent and the Diaspora Workshops, tapes 254-258, 1991-1992, CAAS 20th Anniversary, tapes 259-271, 1991, Race, Culture and the Politics of Intellectual Inquiry Lecture Series, tapes 272-278, 1991-1992, Remapping of Scholarship: African peoples in the Industrial Age, tapes, tapes 279-284, 1994, Graduate Student Conference [became Student of Color of Rackham (SCOR), tapes 285-293, 1991-1993, Barbados, tapes 310-330, 1989, Martin Luther King (MLK) Day, tapes 331-350, 1987-1992, CAAS Mini-course 324: Black Educational Achievement over the Life-Course, tapes 351-361, 1988, and Chronological events, tapes 352-486, 1983-2001. The last named subseries, Chronological events is the largest, comprising 137 recordings. Undated tapes appear at the end of this subseries.
  - Early Recorded Speakers
    - James Banks: World of a Black Child, 1975 June 26; audiocassette; (Lecture by Professor James Banks entitled "World of a Black Child.") (Box 28)
      - [side 1; no side 2], [2012140-SR-1-1]
        [Access to digitized content is enabled for users who are able to authenticate via the University of Michigan weblogin.]
    - James Chaffers: Architecture as Special Responsibility, 1977 November 22; audiocassette; (Lecture by Professor James Chaffers entitled "Architecture as Special Responsibility.") (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-2-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-2-2]
    - Jonas Chenault and Ozzie Edwards: World of Black Child, 1975 June 25; audiocassette; (Lecture entitled "World of Black Child" discussing sociological concerns surrounding African-American children.) (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-3-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-3-2]
    - Chinweizu: The Assault on Industrial Systems on Global Ecology, 1980 October 23; audiocassette; (Lecture by Professor Chinweizu discussing the impact of industry and capitalism on ecology.) (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-4-1]
    - John Henrik Clarke: Walter Rodney and the Black Radical Tradition: An Historical Perspective. First Annual Walter Rodney Memorial Lecture (lecture part of Black History Month), 1982 March 04; audiocassette; (John Henrik Clarke, "Walter Rodney and the Black Radical Tradition: An Historical Perspective."; The First Annual Walter Rodney Memorial Lecture, Thursday, March 4, 1982, Schorling Auditorium, School of Education Building, the University of Michigan - Ann Arbor. Dr. Clarke's Lecture was part of "Black History Month" March 3 and 4; George Norman's "Black Odyssey" pictorial exhibit was on display in Lorch Hall.) (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-5-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-5-2]
    - Ron Daniels: Revitalizing Independent Black Politics: Towards a Strategy for the 1980's, 1978 June 12; audiocassette; (Lecture by Ron Daniels entitled "Revitalizing Independent Black Politics: Towards a Strategy for the 1980's" discussing black politics in the United States.) (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-6-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-6-2]
    - Diggs Lecture: Black History Panel Part1, 1978 February 13; audiocassette; (Part I; Lecture series entitled "South Africa: Implications for Black America") (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-7-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-7-2]
    - Diggs Lecture: Black History Panel Part 2, 1978 February 13; audiocassette; (Part II; Lecture series entitled "South Africa: Implications for Black America") (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-8-1]
    - Isawa Elaigwu: The Barracks and the Ballot Box, 1979 April 04; audiocassette; (Lecture by Dr. Isawa Elaigwu entitled "The Barracks and the Ballot Box.") (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-9-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-9-2]
    - Edgar Epps: School Desegregation, Self-Perception and Achievement, Orientation of Minority Children, undated; audiocassette; (Lecture by Edgar Epps; "School Desegrgation, Self-Perception and Achievment, Orientation of Minority Children" discussing education issues in the African-American community.) (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-10-1]
    - W. Reynolds Farley: Catching up? Recent Trends in the Social and Economic Status of Blacks, 1983 March 02; audiocassette; (Lecture entitled "Catching Up? Recent Trends in the Social and Economic Status of Blacks." Subjects discussed are the changing social and economic in African-American communities.) (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-11-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-11-2]
    - Samuel Gardner: The Justice System and How it Affects Blacks, 1978 February 15; audiocassette; (Lecture by Judge Samuel Gardner on the justice system and its effects on Black community.) (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-12-1] (Box 28)
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-12-2]
    - George Goodman: Black Students at U of M in the 1970's, 1980 February 13; audiocassette; (Tape 1; George Goodman, Dir. Opportunity PGM; Center for Afro-American & African Studies)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-13-1] (Box 28)
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-13-2]
    - George Goodman: Black Students at U of M in the 1970'sf, 1980 February 13; audiocassette; (Tape 1; George Goodman, Director: Opportunity Program; Center for Afro-American & African Studies.)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-14-1] (Box 28)
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-14-2]
    - Bryant Bunyon Goodman and Janice O'Neal: The National Presidential Elections 1980: The Day After, 1980 November 01; audiocassette; (Bryant Bunyon Goodman and Janice O'Neal discuss aftermath of the 1980 Presidential Election.) (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-15-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-15-2]
    - David Gordon: Black African States and the Struggle for Southern Africa, 1979 February 14; audiocassette; (Tape is very noisy. Lecture discussing anti-colonial and independence movements in Southern Africa.) (Box 28)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-16-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-16-2]